

# Milan Klaasman

MSc. Artificial Intelligence

3 November 1993

Amsterdam, Netherlands

+31 625 500 134

milanklaasman@gmail.com

Linked in /in/milan-klaasman

GitHub /MKlaasman

## Summary –

Artificial Intelligence graduate, with affinity for sports, data analytics, machine learning and solving all kinds of puzzles. Focused and dedicated to become an expert in data science. I would describe myself as an enthusiastic, positive, assertive and trustworthy person, with great analytical and problem solving skills. Proficiency in coding using Python (+ R and Matlab) and implementing data mining and machine learning techniques.

## Interests —

Programming (Python)

**Data Analytics** 

Sports (Mostly: Football & Endurance)

Socializing

## **Work Experience**

Feb - Aug 2019 Thesis: Predicting football event outcomes using supervised learn-

ing techniques.

www.metrica-sports.com

Setting up a a new database structure and workflow to analyse tracking and events data of over 350 professional football games using

machine learning techniques.

**Data Acquisition Manager** 2018 - 2019

At Metrica Sports, responsible for managing the daily processes of the Data Acquisition team and the data quality insurance. Analysing and assuring the data quality by using both Python and Matlab.

Feb - Dec 2017 Teacher (Assistant) - Quality assurance programming course

"Java for Software Testers"

At NLBC, I was working as a Teacher/Assistant-Teacher for 2-day

Java programming bootcamps for Software Testers.

2013 - 2017 **Employee in event/catering industry** 

www.tene.nl

www.ah.nl

**VU University** 

Re-stocker and cashier at Albert Heijn 2010 - 2013

### **Education**

2016 - 2019 MSc. Artificial Intelligence **VU University** 

Amsterdam, Netherlands

Track: Research Variant Cognitive Science GPA: 7.5/10

**Bsc. Human Movement Sciences** 2012 - 2016

Amsterdam, Netherlands

Minor: Sport GPA: 6.7/10

#### **Volunteer Work**

**Foundation Move Project** 2014 - 2015 www.stichtingmove.nl

Social entrepreneurship, a neighborhood project in association with

children and the city council of Amsterdam.

Youth football trainer 2008 - 2011

## Other activities

2019-2020 **Travel to China and Nepal** 

2019+2020 Participation in 1st and 2nd DFB Hackathon (German Football As-

sociation), 5 month project

Implementing Clustering techniques to discover insights in crosses

in the game of football.

**Utrecht Full Marathon (Time: 3:42)** 2018

**President of a fraternity of Student Association SSRA** 2015 - 2016

Responsible for organizing meetings, accommodations and activities

for a group of 30 people.

**Internal Board of Student Association SSRA** 2014 - 2015

> As a member of the internal board of student association SSRA, my team and I were responsible for the maintenance of the association

building and enforcement of the rules.